<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tools | Byte Friendly]]></title>
  <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-26T21:18:15+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sergio Tulentsev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dash - now with cheatsheets]]></title>
    <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2014/03/dash-now-with-cheatsheets/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T21:50:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/2014/03/dash-now-with-cheatsheets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a couple of days ago I blogged about <a href="http://kapeli.com/dash">Dash</a>. And now they have released new major version, with (at least one) new feature: cheatsheets. One of the things I just can't hold in my memory is HTTP status codes. I know 200 and 404, that's it. All others I have to look up, every single time. And Dash has a cheatsheet for this, so I am covered here.</p>

<p>There is no cheatsheet for Vim, not even on its movements. But good news is: you can create your own: <a href="https://github.com/Kapeli/cheatset#readme">cheatset</a>.</p>

<p>I shall probably create one for TextMate key shortcuts (I should know most of them by now, I guess). We'll see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful documentation lookup tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2014/03/useful-documentation-lookup-tools/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T23:20:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/2014/03/useful-documentation-lookup-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I just wanted to share some tools that I use to read documentation.</p>

<p>First one is <a href="http://kapeli.com/dash">Dash</a>. It's an offline documentation browser which contains many different topics. It has ruby, rails, CSS, HAML, jQuery, Go, Haskell and everything else you might want. It can also index locally installed rubygems. And did I mention that it is offline? If you're anything like me, you need to consult documentation every 30 seconds. And with this tool you can even work on a plane! Can't recommend enough.</p>

<p>Another one is for ruby only, <a href="http://www.omniref.com/">OmniRef</a>. These guys have indexed every ruby gem there is and cross-linked the documentation. On the site you can <em>easily</em> switch between version of a gem (or ruby) and see how documented behaviour and/or code changed over time. It also allows leaving notes (user generated content?), but I don't see many notes at the moment. Potentially, these comments can be an excellent complement to the official documentation (we see this with, say, MySQL docs).</p>

<p>And, of course, the most important tool for me these days is <a href="http://stackoverflow.com">StackOverflow</a>. More than half of my google searches lead to this chest of collective programming wisdom. The funniest moments are when I struggle with something, then google points me to stackoverflow where I find an answer that <em>I posted myself</em> some time ago. Can you believe this? :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hide/exclude directories in TextMate 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2013/10/hide-slash-exclude-directories-in-textmate-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-30T10:24:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/2013/10/hide-slash-exclude-directories-in-textmate-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to give TextMate 2 another try today. Hopefully it won't freeze upon trying to install a bundle like it did last time. Now I don't recall which bundle was that, but so far things are going well. Mostly.</p>

<p>When I opened my Rails app and tried to navigate to file (<code>Cmd+T</code>), I saw this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/uploads/2013/10/30/tm2_tmp_files.png"></p>

<p>At first I thought that these are files from <code>.git</code> folder and spent embarrassing amount of time trying to make TM2 hide that folder. But these are actually temp asset files generated by Sprockets and they reside in <code>tmp/assets/...</code>.</p>

<p>Long story short, here's how you can hide a directory in TextMate 2, both from project browser and navigation dialog.</p>

<p>Create a <code>.tm_properties</code> file. It can be in current project dir or any parent dir (up to <code>$HOME</code>). Put this line into it.</p>

<p><code>
excludeDirectories = "{tmp,}"
</code></p>

<p>It is worth noting that <code>"{tmp}"</code> doesn't work. Apparently, TextMate glob parser breaks down if it can't find a comma. So we add one. Alternatively we can use this line:</p>

<p><code>
excludeDirectories = "{$excludeDirectories,tmp}"
</code></p>

<p>It will amend an existing <code>excludeDirectories</code> setting (empty string by default) instead of replacing. And it also has a comma. :)</p>

<p>Hope this post saved you some time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
