<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Software reviews | Byte Friendly]]></title>
  <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/blog/categories/software-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-29T02:29:35+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sergio Tulentsev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making more mockups]]></title>
    <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2009/03/making-more-mockups/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-03T19:29:10+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/2009/03/making-more-mockups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today Elen, my manager, approached me and asked to make a prototype of a new functionality in our project management system. This is a reimbursement management module: employees spend some money (taxi from airport, for example), then they create requests for reimbursements and if they are lucky and management approves the requests, they get the money back :-)</p>

<p>So, prototype it is. I fired up my <a href="http://balsamiq.com/products/mockups/desktop">Balsamiq for Desktop </a>and in under ten minutes mockups of two pages were ready. This is one of them:</p>

<p><a href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/03/manager_view.png"><img src="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/03/manager_view.png" alt="manager_view" /></a></p>

<p>But when I sent them to Elen, I thought that maybe she meant some real code, or HTML stubs in real system, because there was a mockup attached to her original email. Here it is:</p>

<p><a href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/03/reembolso.jpg"><img src="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/03/reembolso-300x159.jpg" alt="reembolso" /></a>According to her, she made it in Paint (<strong>duh!</strong>). And it took her approximately 30 minutes to make this one, because she had to printscreen some real pages and cut pieces from them. What a tedious work! :-) And it must be a hell to modify such mockup!</p>

<p>When I told her about <a href="http://balsamiq.com/">Balsamiq Mockups</a>, she became very interested and decided to give it a try. Another happy story. Thank you, Peldi :-)</p>

<p>Related posts: <a href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2008/12/creating-ui-mockups-with-balsamiq/">Creating UI mockups with Balsamiq</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating UI mockups with Balsamiq]]></title>
    <link href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/2008/12/creating-ui-mockups-with-balsamiq/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-18T18:53:28+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tech.tulentsev.com/2008/12/creating-ui-mockups-with-balsamiq</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Virtually in every project you have to do some UI mockups. I mean, if you have some methodology, you are a team and you are serious about your project.</p>

<p>In my past experience I have tried different ways of creating mockups:</p>

<ol>
<li>hand-drawn pictures;</li>
<li>hand-drawn pictures, photographed with digital camera and inserted into requirement doc;</li>
<li>Visio documents (duh!);</li>
<li>some actual code.</li>
</ol>


<p>While the last way serves some extra purposes (other than creating mockup itself), it takes a lot of time. And sometime you just need to share with others a picture you have in your head. Ways #1 and #2 serve very well, but have one <strong>major</strong> disadvantage: if you want to modify a picture, you have to redraw it from scratch (or make a mess from the original one). And yeah, Visio way does more harm than good: it takes enormous time to create a picture and then you often "forget" to update a mockup, because you don't want to launch that app again.</p>

<p>So, what options do we have?</p>

<p>Recently I discovered an excellent piece of software, called Balsamiq Mockups. It is simple, effective and nice looking. It requires zero learning time. For example, I tried to create something for my personal project, yet another photo gallery. And I got this mockup ready in exactly 6 minutes after I started the demo:</p>

<p><a href="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/01/image5.png"><img src="http://tech.tulentsev.com/images/uploads/2009/01/image-thumb5.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>Impressions: product - great, support - fast and fully satisfying, overall - have to get one.</p>

<p>Also I want to quote <a href="http://www.facebook.com/s.php?k=100000080&amp;id=1162968534">Charles William Stanton</a> here:</p>

<blockquote><p>Before, I was doing far too little GUI "prototyping" because either the results weren't reusable or the effort took too long; now I fear I may be doing too much because it's just that much fun.</p></blockquote>

<p>Go to the <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/products/mockups">product web site</a> and see it for yourself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
